# LUKEMITCHELL

# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Updated October 14th 2016

#### ABOUT ME

A software developer, UI designer, technology consultant and a blue-sky thinker. I've worked as a cryptocurrency developer for a number of small FinTech startups. A creative thinker, I'm self motivated and an experienced team leader. I've developed a hobby operating system, several cryptocurrencies and a magnetic stylus for guiding the user as they point. I speak basic German.

I enjoy travelling, climbing, taking photographs and yoga. I've cycled 2400 kilometers across the Alps, and I've hitchhiked across Europe. I'm an environmentalist, a climate-change activist and a keen vegetarian cook.

You can find me online at <a href="www.lukemitchell.co">www.lukemitchell.co</a> and my open-source projects at <a href="www.github.com/lukem512">www.github.com/lukem512</a>. I'm on Linked In at <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/lukemitchell2016">www.github.com/lukem512</a>. I'm on Linked In at <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/lukemitchell2016">www.lukemitchell.co</a> and my open-source projects at <a href="www.github.com/lukem512">www.github.com/lukem512</a>. I'm on Linked In at <a href="www.github.com/lukemitchell2016">www.github.com/lukem512</a>. I'm on Linked In at <a href="www.github.com/lukemitchell2016">www.github.com/lukemitchell2016</a>.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Enki

July 2016 to date

I currently work as a full-stack developer with Enki, developers of a microlearning app for teaching developer skills. I am working with JavaScript and React to create a hybrid iOS/Android application within a small team. The role also includes website and database admin, toolchain development and feature design.

Skills: Node.js, React, web, back-end, front-end, gamification

# **University of Bristol: Research Contractor**

May 2016 to July 2016 (6 weeks)

I was enlisted by my dissertation supervisors to assist a research project after the completion of my degree. The project, named *IODiCUS*, involved creating a generic gateway to be used for the intelligent analysis of power usage and generation across the university estates, with the aim being a reduction in consumption and cost. During this time I created test frameworks, performed refactoring and aided in design decision-making.

Skills: Software design, Linux, Python, Node.js, Docker

# **Technology Consultant**

February 2014 to date

I am currently working as a freelance consultant, specialising in developing cryptocurrency applications for FinTech startups. I have worked with other developers and, latterly, as a technical adviser to launch products including a gold-backed blockchain, an encrypted messenger with an integrated wallet and an array of supporting software. My recent clients include The Real Asset Co. and StartJOIN Holdings Ltd.

Skills: Software design, UI, JavaScript, C++, web, mobile, cryptocurrency

**Cambridge Consultants: Technology Scholar** 

# September 2010 to September 2012 (1 year, 3 months)

I spent a year working as an intern with Cambridge Consultants before starting my degree. During this time I was a member of several internal development teams including an intern-led project developing a 'whitespace' WiFi network. I returned the following summer to work for the business following my first year of University. During this time I worked on a variety of client projects including a testing framework for the Highways Agency, a UI mockup for Novartis and a survey framework. During my time there I billed more client hours than any previous Technology Scholar.

Skills: Software development, project organisation, C#, PHP, Linux, wireless

# **VOLUNTEERING**

# **Hungry Caterpillar Food Co-op**

September 2012 to date

I am the president of a student not-for-profit co-operative. The organisation helps students make ethical food choices by providing a weekly pop-up shop selling organic and fairtrade produce, sourced from local suppliers. The co-operative has dozens of members and the organisation requires social media management, stock-taking and charisma. We were awarded the Volunteers for Food award at the Bristol Green Volunteering Awards in 2016.

# **Callington Road Psychiatric Hospital**

2013

I have volunteered for an organisation that visits a psychiatric hospital to talk to patients, play games with them and generally alleviate the monotony of hospital life. I found this to be a challenging and moving experience that I enjoyed immensely.

#### Other

I have volunteered at various projects including Food Cycle, the University of Bristol Botanical Gardens, the Bristol University Sustainability Team and the COP21 climate march. I have helped prepare food for a large number of people, performed website upgrades and acted as a steward.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Force Attraction Pen: A Haptic Pen with Variable Attraction Force, Burnside, Elgar, Healer, Hill, Ioannidis, Mitchell, Worgan and Roudaut. In Proceedings of CHI EA'16. Late Breaking Work. To appear 2016.

#### EDUCATION

**MEng Computer Science** (Second Class Honours: First Division)

University of Bristol July 2016

Final project: "A Digital Platform for Conducting Research into Social Pledges"

A level Computer Science, Maths, Philosophy (Grades A, A, B)

**AS level Electronics** (Grade A)

Hills Road Sixth Form, Cambridge June 2010

### **REFEREES**

# Dr. Chris Preist

Reader in Sustainability and Computer Systems University of Bristol chris.preist@bristol.ac.uk

# Dr. Julian Gough

Professor of Bioinformatics University of Bristol julian.gough@bristol.ac.uk

# Jon Edgcombe

Group Leader
Cambridge Consultants Ltd.
jon.edgcombe@cambridgeconsultants.com